Auditions begin.
Sing is a family, comedy, music film directed by Garth Jennings.
A koala named Buster recruits his best friend to help him drum up
business for his theater by hosting a singing competition.
Buster Moon (voice), played by Matthew McConaughey.
Rosita (voice), played by Reese Witherspoon.
Mike (voice), played by Seth MacFarlane.
Ash (voice), played by Scarlett Johansson.
Eddie (voice), played by John C. Reilly.
Johnny (voice), played by Taron Egerton.
Sing is a 2016 American animated jukebox musical comedy film written and directed by Garth
Jennings, produced by Illumination Entertainment, and distributed by Universal Pictures.
The film stars the voices of Matthew McConaughey, Reese
Witherspoon, Seth MacFarlane, Scarlett Johansson, John C.
Reilly, Taron Egerton, Tori Kelly, Jennifer Saunders,
Jennifer Hudson, Peter Serafinowicz and Nick Kroll.
Set in a world inhabited by anthropomorphic animals, the film focuses on a koala named Buster Moon, a struggling theater owner who stages a singing competition in
an effort to prevent his theater from entering foreclosure, as well as how the competition interferes with the personal lives of its contestants.
The film features more than 60 songs from famous
artists, mostly performed diegetically.
It also has an original song by Stevie Wonder and Ariana Grande
called "Faith", which was nominated for a Golden Globe.
Aside from these songs, Joby Talbot (Jennings’ frequent
collaborator) composed the film's score.
Sing first screened during the Toronto International Film Festival on September 11, 2016,
followed by its premiere at the Microsoft Theater in Los Angeles on December 3.
It was then theatrically released in the United States on December 21.
It marked the first time Illumination released two films in the same year,
following the release of The Secret Life of Pets six months earlier.
It received mostly positive reviews and grossed $634
million worldwide on a $75 million budget.
A sequel, Sing 2, was released on December 22, 2021.
The film explores themes of anthropomorphism, singing,
animals, flood, singing competition.
The tone is lighthearted.